Guide to the Research Material about Robert Noyce
Department of Special Collections
Research material about Robert Noyce
ca. 1970-2005
M1491
Berlin, Leslie
9 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection documents the research phase of Berlin's biography of Robert Noyce, entitled THE MAN BEHIND THE MICROCHIP. Included are interviews and transcripts including one with Gordon Moore.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Leslie Berlin, 2005. Accession 2005-245.
Biography / Administrative History
Leslie Berlin received her Ph.D. in History from Stanford in 2001. She is currently (2005) a visiting scholar in the Program in the History and Philosophy of Science and Technology. She is also the Project Historian for the Silicon Valley Archives at Stanford.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of photographs, transcripts and audiotapes of interviews, speeches given by Noyce and others, and background research on the history of the micro-chip industry and the growth of Silicon Valley. Broken down into 8 series, the material includes information on individual corporations that Noyce helped found or managed, including Fairchild Seimconductor and Intel.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Moore, Gordon.; Noyce, Robert N., 1927-; Computer Engineering.; Science--History.; Semiconductors.; Electronics--Research--California--Santa Clara County.
Container List
- Series 1: Noyce Biography
  - Photos (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photos includes discs and negatives (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Grinnell Physics Dept - Grant Gale (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Noyce Articles About Him (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bonner's Pamphlet, Wolfe Article, Lowood Article, Adam Noyce Thesis (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Noyce Interviews (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Noyce as Father (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Funeral Personal (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Noyce Speeches/Writings (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - RNN Speeches (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Noyce Speeches (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Betty Noyce, Marriage (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - From Scotland to California: Tait, Douglas and Norton Ancestorsby Nancy Anne and Donald Sterling Noyce (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Faded Homesteads by Donald Noyce (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Noyce Memorabilia (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Silicon Valley History
  - Built Environment (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Business History and Economic History (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Electronics Industry Stats/Background (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Early Silicon Valley Electronics (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hewlett Packard (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Regional Competitiveness (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Semiconductor Industry (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Silicon Valley Economy/Electronics - Post 80 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Unionization (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Venture Capital (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bell Labs/Transistor (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Hoefler - 19691969 Dec 29 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Integrated Circuit (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - IC - Rostky (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - IC Chapter on Hold (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Innovation Nos. 20, 1971 and 8, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - EE Times 25th Anniversary Issue October 30, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Fairchild Semiconductor
  - Planar Tech/Planar License, Noyce Patents (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lab Books - Noyce, Moore, Hoerni (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - IC Tech and Marketing (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Early Technical Articles (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Shockley (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fairchild Start Up (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - AR Notes, Corporate Structure, Corporate Growth, Distributors (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Micrologic Materials (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fairchild - Old Films, Videotape (Box 7)
  - Micrologic Materials (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Key Players - Bios (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Problems1966 - 1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Spinouts, Industry Development (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Integrated Circuit Patent Dispute (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photos (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Japan (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jay Last Materials (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Series 4: U.S. Response to Japanese Competition
  - US/Japan Semiconductor Agreement1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Defense and Government (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Electronics Lobbying Associations (not SIA) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - US/Japan Industry Comments (not Noyce) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Industrial Policy - International Competition (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Noyce Lobbying (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Competition (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Semiconductor Industry Association (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - SIA (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Japan Semiconductor Market Access: Background and Source Book by the Semiconductor Industry Association (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Series 5: Intel
  - Oral Histories - Stein (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Moore, Gordon / Moore's Law (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Problems 1980's (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Oral Histories - Stein Cont. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Secondary Sources - Academic (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Stock / Pay Incentives (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Strategy (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - (MGT) Strategy (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Systems / End of Ch (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Probably Won't Use (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - SEC Filings (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Semiconductor Startups Intel Archives1986 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Competitors - (small) Mostek 4 Phase AMI (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Intel #1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Rev in Progress + 25 Year Retrospective (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Intel Press 1973 - 1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Intel #2 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 432 (Failed follow on to 8088) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1103 / AMI Competition (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Intel Benefits (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Custom vs. Standard (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Customers (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Defectors / Spinoffs (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Intel - Early Years (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Foundry (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Employees mgt, ranking, recruiting (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Finance (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Intel - General Background (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1969 - 1971 + Tedd Hoff materials (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Intel 1972 -1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - History 1971 - 1974 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - History 1974 - 1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - IBM - Intel (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Microprocessor (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Memories Market (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Series 6: Sematech
  - Lobbying Drafts (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Misc. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - RNN at Sematech / RNN chosen CEO (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Site Selection, Austin / SV Reaction (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Series 7: Post - Intel Startups
  - Callanish (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Caere (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Censtor (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Coherant (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Control Data (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Diasonics (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Four - Phase (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Melchor / Osborne (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Monoclonal (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Sanoma Cutrer (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - ROLM (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - San Jose Jet Center (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Superconductor Technologies (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Tom Campbell - Tort Reform (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Varadyne (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Volant Ski (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Series 8: Interviews
  - Transcripts [1 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Transcripts [2 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Consent Forms (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Bob Norman [2] (Box 17, Othertype 1)
  - Fred Hoar [2] (Box 17, Othertype 2)
  - Richard Hodgeson [2] (Box 17, Othertype 3)
  - Harry Sello [2] (Box 17, Othertype 4)
  - Eugene Kleimer [2] (Box 17, Othertype 5)
  - Bruce Mackay [2] (Box 17, Othertype 6)
  - Paul Hwoschinsky [2] (Box 17, Othertype 7)
  - Charlie Sporck [2] (Box 17, Othertype 8)
  - Roger Borovoy [2] (Box 17, Othertype 9)
  - John Reed [2] (Box 17, Othertype 10)
  - Miller Bonner [2] (Box 17, Othertype 11)
  - Jean Jones (Box 17, Othertype 12)
  - Gene Fluth [2] (Box 17, Othertype 13)
  - Don Kobrin (Box 17, Othertype 14)
  - Arthur Rock (Box 17, Othertype 15)
  - Nelson Stone (Box 17, Othertype 16)
  - Ed Gelbach (Box 17, Othertype 17)
  - Regis McKenna [3] (Box 17, Othertype 18)
  - Sheldon Roberts [4] (Box 17, Othertype 19)
  - Jim Gibbons [2] (Box 17, Othertype 20)
  - Gordon Moore [2] (Box 17, Othertype 21)
  - Transcript Files [9] (Box 17, Othertype 22)